It's almost here…
The old man's ship.
Right on time.
He's about twenty minutes away.
I-Is Mr. Joseph Joestar
the only passenger?
Yeah.
The rest of the crew is made up of
folks from the Speedwagon Foundation.
Chili Pepper may be
confined to areas of electricity,
but I'm sure that
won't stop him from trying to
pass over the water and
onto the old man's ship.
If he gets to him first, we lose.
He'll kill the old man.
Jotaro!
The boat looks good.
As far as the battery goes,
he's not hiding in there.
We're all clear and ready to go.
Josuke…
Okuyasu and I are the only ones
heading to meet the old man.
Huh?
You will hold the fort here
with Koichi.
Stay here?! With Josuke?
Why?
Josuke, Chili Pepper's user is hiding
somewhere here in this harbor,
watching us.
He's waiting for us to make our move,
so he can confirm the boat's position.
And my hunch is he won't be
hiding on a boat.
All he needs is a battery and
something faster than a motorboat.
Just like the bike,
PORT OF MORIOH
he'll find something with a battery and
send Chili Pepper flying on that.
Flying? You mean up in the sky?
Yeah.
I wouldn't be surprised if Chili Pepper
was making off with
a remote-controlled plane as we speak.
A remote-controlled airplane?!
It's possible!
Once they pick up speed,
model airplanes can fly over 100 kph!
That's faster than this motorboat.
And because
Chili Pepper's controlling it,
he can fly as far and as high as
the battery will take him!
He doesn't need
a remote control's signal!
Josuke, if you spot anything
flying around here,
I want you to search for his user.
Koichi's Reverb has
a range of fifty meters.
He can help.
If he beats us to the punch,
the old man is done for.
You will safeguard your father
from terra firm a!
Understand, Josuke?
Yeah, I'm well aware
we don't have a second to spare.
JOJO'S BIZARRE ADVENTURE
DIAMOND IS UNBREAKABLE
These faceless gazes pass by one another
A wound to the heart changes our everyday
Encounters without boundaries
The bizarre is our normal U-yeh
These ordinary mornings,
we're laughing on the surface
Mysteries drawn to each other,
identity still unknown
Without a heads up,
it's quietly lurking somewhere in this town
Although we bicker and complain
In the end, we celebrate
Dancing through the everyday
Crazy Noisy Bizarre Town
EPISODE 12
CHILI PEPPER, PART 2
Good luck, Okuyasu.
Thanks, Koichi.
In just about twenty minutes,
we'll arrive at
the Port of Morioh, Mr. Joestar.
Is that so? Uh…
Would you happen to know
where my cane is?
Um, isn't that it right there
in front of you?
Ahh…
My own father, huh…
Josuke? Are you all right?
Out of the blue, I'm told a man
I've never met is my father…
It's… I don't know…
But, his life's in danger.
Not doing everything I can
would haunt my dreams forever.
Besides, my mom would break down in
a puddle of tears if he ever bit the dust.
Damn! It must've been Jotaro!
If he left you two behind
to sniff out my user…
Then he completely saw through
my remote-controlled plane trick!
Chili Pepper!
Yeah!
Jotaro Kujo is sharp as a tack.
And he's the last person
I want finding me.
This remote-controlled Spitfire plane
can reach Joseph Joestar's boat
in a mere five minutes.
A motorboat, on the other hand,
will take about eight to ten.
Meaning, if I put the two
of you down in about three minutes,
I can catch up and
pass them with time to spare.
Y-You're Chili Pepper's user?
You're looking at Akira Otoishi,
age nineteen.
Oh, and don't mind this guitar.
One day, I want to be
an ultra super guitarist
who lives hard and fast,
just like Jimi Hendrix and Jeff Beck!
That's why I keep
this baby on me at all times!
And before you know it,
I'm gonna be knocking out…
people all over the world
with this guitar!
Oh, yeah.
I never would've thought.
A Stand user out in the open.
Which means,
there's not a doubt in his mind
that he can slaughter
Josuke and me both!
YEEEES
Against your Shining Diamond,
I'll use nothing but my little ol' pinky,
just like I did with Okuyasu.
Get back, Koichi.
It's game on, Josuke Higashikata!
One sec, please.
Huh?
If you're going to use only your pinky,
then I've got some rules, too.
Rules? You better learn some respect!
Rules are wasted on a punk like you!
How dare you, you bastard?!
Well, you said rules are wasted on me.
Weren't you saying something about
bringing me down with your little pinky?
So what'll it be,
big-shot senior, Otoishi?
I'm gonna destroy you.
You already said that!
You can stop
repeating yourself, dumb-ass!
The pain, the agony…
I must redirect it onto something!
This rage…
I have to vent to someone!
He's amazing…
RIGHT-HAND TAPPING
I'M GOING TO KILL
YOUR MOMMIES, TOO!
I just set my heart free!
I just let that blistering rage fly.
Try me, Otoishi!
Wh-What? The user just…
I know Stands can move
at incredible speed,
but a user bolting behind me?
Th-That's not it, Josuke!
I saw everything from back here!
Otoishi didn't move…
The one who moved was you!
Something moved you!
What?
Chili Pepper appeared and
flipped Shining Diamond
around 180 degrees in a flash!
You're facing the ocean, aren't you?
Chili Pepper appeared?
Koichi! I haven't seen
that bastard Chili Pepper anywhere!
He's underground!
Look at all the storm drains!
He poked himself halfway
out of the drain just now!
There must be electrical lines
running all over under there!
A little soul-searching
always fires me up.
Behind you on your right!
Now he's right behind you!
He keeps bolting back into
the electrical wires at the last second!
And at light speed!
Jotaro's the only one
who can keep up!
You don't have the luxury
of digging up the asphalt
and severing the wires,
Josuke Higashikata.
And the bigger the opening you make…
the easier it is for me
to surface from below!
Josuke! To your right!
In front of you!
Behind you!
No, wait! Um…
It's like super expert level
whack-a-mole!
I can't follow his movements
at that speed!
Guessing really isn't going
to get you anywhere!
Josuke…
And I still have two minutes left…
That's plenty of time
to do away with you.
Koichi, watch for Chili Pepper's
location and report it me.
I'm too close to tell!
I-I can't tell, either!
Just when I think he's out,
he goes back in!
Look harder, Koichi.
You should be able to tell
what I'm thinking by now.
Huh? What you're thinking?
I-It's all squishy!
The asphalt's turned into tar…
The drains are covered
in oil from the tar!
I get it!
When he struck the ground,
he reduced the asphalt to
its most basic ingredients!
Which means…
Behind you, to your left!
Yeah! Bull's eye!
Bull's eye? That's great.
Do I get a prize
if I smack him around some more?
CHILI PEPPER
It's the boat!
We're close enough
I can read its number!
W-We're almost there!
Don't let your guard down yet.
Huh?
Wh-What the hell is that?
Josuke! Koichi!
That light!
It seems I didn't take you nearly
serious enough, Josuke Higashikata.
I should lose my juvenile thinking,
shouldn't I?
I'm focusing all of Morioh's
electricity into Chili Pepper!
I'm only doing this now
because it temporarily
reduces my power source,
this entire region's electricity,
to nothing!
But I don't care anymore!
After I crush you fools, all I have to do
is use the RC plane's battery
to fly to Joseph and kill him!
I-I can't see!
You bastard…
He totally overwhelmed Josuke!
Josuke!
Don't you see?
This entire town's electrical power
is at my disposal!
I'll be sure to tack on
my entire electric bill
onto your meter.
It's lights out, Josuke!
Is this a tire?!
By the time you figure it out,
it'll be way too late.
You blew up that tire
on purpose, didn't you?
It was all to entomb
my Stand in rubber!
Of course! Tire rubber is an insulator,
so it doesn't conduct electricity!
Chili Pepper can't use electricity!
Dammit!
Yes! Now we just have
to wait for Jotaro…
Just kidding.
Huh?
So you think you can insulate
me with rubber?
Maybe it would've worked
if it had been a meter thick!
Don't make me laugh!
Like this flimsy rubber
could've done anything!
Dummy!
You've lost, Josuke!
Great. You'd be a lot better off
if you hadn't had the strength
to break through that tire.
Th-The air in the tire!
It was completely full?!
N-Not the ocean! Anything but that!
O-Oh, yeah…
Salt water conducts electricity
The vastness of the ocean means
the electricity scatters in every direction!
I'm sorry! Please!
- Get me out of here!
- You said something about
wanting to lose your juvenile thinking.
But that, my friend,
is a permanent character flaw.
I-I'm dissolving…
His Stand's been diffused!
Which means…
H-He's dead?
Jotaro!
We defeated the user!
We defeated Chili Pepper's user!
Well done.
We can all breathe a little easier.
So this is Josuke's dad..
He looks huge, but the geezer
looks like he's on his last legs.
You there,
what's your name?
Okuyasu.
Okuyasu?
I live in Josuke's neighborhood;
I'm a Stand user, too.
Huh?
A Stand user.
A S-t-a-n-d u-s-e-r!
Ah, you bought
a second-hand computer?
I'm a Stand user!
Oh, is that it?!
You're a Stand user.
It's no picnic.
By the way, Osomatsu,
I can't seem to find my cane.
Do you know where it is?
Ah!
Oh silly me.
I'm holding it here in my hand.
Is this old-timer okay?
Mr. Joestar.
I've come to pick up your luggage.
By the way, Osomatsu,
I'd like to know.
Has Josuke mentioned me?
The man who for sixteen years
didn't know he was born…
Has he said anything at all?
Can't say he's said much about that.
Is that so. So he hasn't…
Yay! They're finally here!
Look, Josuke!
Oh, that's good news, I guess.
To be honest,
I kinda wish he'd just go back home.
Josuke…
Well, I am glad Otoishi didn't kill him.
Now everyone can
live happily ever after.
But you know…
I've never even met him.
How can I think of him as my dad?
It's gonna be totally awkward
for both of us.
It's not like I hate him or anything.
But I have to think about my mom, too.
Don't you think, Koichi?
O-Oh, no…
Josuke, more trouble!
H-His body!
Jotaro, we're in big trouble!
Akira Otoishi's body is gone!
He's still
alive!
Bad news!
The enemy has infiltrated our ship!
Akira Otoishi is still alive!
Are you kidding?
Take Mr. Joestar…
Who are you?
Huh? Did you say something?
No, he…
I said it!
He's not from
the Speedwagon Foundation!
Wha…
What?!
He's the enemy!
You sure 'bout that? Bastard!
Wait!
I'm the one who told you
about the enemy!
Would any enemy do that?!
This man is the enemy!
He's got a point!
I pointed out the enemy
in the first place!
He came here to
throw you off your guard!
He's got a point, too…
Wh-Who's the user?
- He is!
Dammit!
Another decision?
Goddammit.
This is what I get
for relying on Bro my whole life…
Okuyasu'll be easy to dispose of
And Jotaro hasn't seen my face yet.
As long as I kill Joseph…
I'll get out of here!
They'll never catch me!
Chili Pepper!
Huh? What's that about
a smelly setter?
Time to die!
I figured out!
The user is…
You!
Nobody fools Okuyasu Nijimura twice!
H-How'd you know?
You wanna know?
How…
I was gonna beat
the shit out of you both!
I'm not too smart, you know.
Watch…
your step.
You'll fall in the water.
S-Sorry.
If I had my cane,
I could manage by myself.
But it broke a moment ago…
G-Guess I don't have a choice.
Grab my hand.
I just had a great idea!
If Shining Diamond fixes the cane…
Y-You dolt! What are you saying?
That was really dumb, Okuyasu!
Huh? Why?
'Cause this is one time leaving it
broken is better.
Huh? Why?
Why is that?
Now if we can just take back
the bow and arrow, it'll all be over…
Not to mention,
this town'll be safe.
EPISODE 13
WE PICKED UP SOMETHING CRAZY!